xeroshoes.com 2018-12-14

# Privacy - Xero Shoes

[](http://secure.trust-guard.com/privacy/8867)Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have developed this Policy  
in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate and make use  
of personal information, and how the law affects and protects you.

The following outlines our Privacy Policy.

Feel The World, Inc., doing business as Xero Shoes, (“we”, “us”, “the Company”, “our”) is the controller and is responsible for your personal data. Our DPM (data privacy manager) is Steven Sashen, CEO. You can contact our DPM at support@xeroshoes.com or via mail at 100 Technology Drive, Suite 315, Broomfield, CO 80021.

We hope that if you have any questions, requests or complaints about our data collection and use and about this policy that you contact us first so that we may address any situation that arises.

Please note that should our site include links to third-party websites over which we have no control, that you read the privacy documents of those websites.

**No SPAM!**

If you share you email address with us for any reason we will not sell, rent, or  
otherwise make your email address available to any third parties for any reason.  
Nor will we barrage you with sales messages. By purchasing from us, you are  
agreeing to receive emails about your order, about special events, and to receive  
our newsletter.

Should you choose to stop receiving email from us, there will be clear instructions at  
the bottom of each email for you to follow to “opt-out.” Emails about specific orders  
(e.g. shipping confirmation) will not have opt-out instructions.

**General Information about the data we collect  
**

When accessing our Website, Feel The World, Inc. will learn certain information about  
you during your visit.

The types of information we collect may include the following (we do not necessarily collect all of this data):

  * Identity — e.g. your name, birth date, gender
  * Contact — e.g. billing and shipping addresses, email address, phone numbers
  * Financial — e.g. payment data (we do not store credit card data at this time)
  * Transactional — e.g. order data, ordered items, time and date of orders, refunds, exchanges, etc.
  * Technical — e.g. IP address (see below), login times and days, browser type and version, geo location and time zones, operating systems, and other data related to the device and software you use to interact with our website and products
  * Profile – e.g. user names, passwords (we are unable to see your passwords as they are encrypted), survey and feedback responses
  * Reviews
  * Usage — e.g. information about how you interact with our site
  * Communication — e.g. your preferences about which types of communication you would like to receive from us and/or third-parties

If we are required to collect any type of personal data by law, and you choose not to provide it, we may not be able to provide you with goods or services. Should this require us to cancel or amend any order with us, we will contact you for resolution.

We may also collect, use, and share non-identifying “aggregate data” for any reason. This is information that is derived from the data above but is not deemed personal as it does not reveal your identity in any way. For example, aggregate data about the number or percentage of users who view a certain page or access a function or feature of our site or purchase certain products.

We do not collect “Special Categories” of personal data such as race, ethnicity, religious beliefs, sexual orientation, political opinions, health and biometric data, criminal history, etc.

**Ways we collect data**

There are various ways we can collect data from you. We do not necessarily use all of the following:

  * Direct contact — e.g. you enter your data by filling out forms when you place an order, subscribe to our publications, enter sweepstakes or contests, request information, provide reviews and feedback.
  * Third party data — e.g. data from publicly available sources such as analytics providers (e.g. Google), advertising networks such as Facebook, Pinterest, Quora, financial transactional data from payment services such as PayPal, etc.
  * Automated technologies — we may collect Technical data using server logs, or “cookies” that reside on our site or other sites using our cookies (see explanation below, “What Are Cookies?”). Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web site, your IP address.

**What Are Cookies?**

A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique  
identifier. When you visit a Web site, that site’s computer asks your computer  
for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically  
designated for cookies. Each Web site can send its own cookie to your browser  
if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser  
only permits a Web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not  
the cookies sent to you by other sites.

**IP Addresses**

IP addresses are used by your computer every time you are connected to the  
Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network  
to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web  
server as part of demographic and profile data known as “traffic data”  
so that data (such as the Web pages you request) can be sent to you.

**Email Information**

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content  
of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We  
provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ  
in the maintenance of information received online, mail and telephone.

**How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?**

Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering  
our business activities, providing customer service and making available other  
items and services to our customers and prospective customers.

Feel The World, Inc. will not obtain personally-identifying information about you when you  
visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us, nor will  
such information be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties  
without the approval of the user at the time of collection.

We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words,  
when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection  
of our legal rights.

Should we sell, transfer, or merge our business with a third-party, your data may transferred as part of that transaction. If that should occur, the third-party owners may use your data in the same manner described in this document. We will require third-parties to similarly treat and respect your data in accordance with the law. We will notify you should such a transaction occur.

**Data security**

We have security measures in place to protect your data from accidental loss, access, use, alteration, or disclosure. We limit the access to your data to employees, agents, contractors and other third-parties who have a business need for that data. They will only access this data per our instructions and subject to non-disclosure.

We will notify you and any necessary authorities should we suspect a data breach to have occurred.

**Data retention**

We will retain personal data only for as long as necessary for fulfilling the purposes for which is was collected and for satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements.

**Deletion of data**

In certain circumstances you may have rights regarding your personal data, including:

  * Requesting access to your personal data
  * Requesting correction or updating of your data
  * Requesting removal of your personal data
  * Objecting to processing your personal data
  * Requesting restriction of processing your personal data
  * Requesting transfer of your personal data
  * Withdrawing consent

Should you wish to exercise any of these rights, contact us at support@xeroshoes.com

In order to comply, we may need to request specific information from you to confirm your identity, ensure your right to access your data or to exercise other rights. We do this to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to anyone who does not have the right to receive it. We may contact you to get further information so that we can provide an accurate and timely response to your request.

We will try to respond to all legitimate requests within 30 days, though it may take longer depending on the nature and quantity of your requests and the total requests received. Should we assess that the time to respond will exceed 30 days, we will notify you with updates to the status of your request.

Should your request be repetitive, excessive, or clearly unfounded, we my assess a fee for compliance or refuse to comply.

**  
A Special Note About Children**

Children are not eligible to use our web site and services and we ask that  
minors (under the age of 13) do not submit any personal information to us. If  
you are a minor, you can use this site only in conjunction with permission and  
guidance from your parents or guardians.

**How Do We Protect Your Information and Secure Information Transmissions?**

Email is not recognized as a secure medium of communication. For this reason,  
we request that you do not send private information to us by email. However,  
doing so is allowed, but at your own risk. Some of the information you may enter  
on our Web site may be transmitted securely via a secure medium known as Secure  
Sockets Layer, or SSL. Credit Card information is never transmitted via email.

Feel The World, Inc. may use software programs to create summary statistics, which are used  
for such purposes as assessing the number of visitors to the different sections  
of our site, what information is of most and least interest, determining technical  
design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas.

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available  
to all users, Feel The World, Inc. uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify  
unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

**Opting out**

You can ask us to stop sending marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links in any marketing message we send you or by contact us at support@xeroshoes.com.

We do not provide opt-out options for transactional emails such as order confirmation, shipping confirmation, tracking, etc.

**Policy Changes**

We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy at any time with or without  
notice. However, please be assured that if the Privacy Policy changes in the  
future, we will not use the personal information you have submitted to us under  
this Privacy Policy in a manner that is materially inconsistent with this Privacy  
Policy, without your prior consent.

We are committed to conducting our business in accordance with these principles  
in order to ensure that the confidentiality of personal information is protected  
and maintained.

**  
Contact**

If you have any questions regarding this Policy, or your dealings with our  
web site, please contact us.

Feel The World, Inc.  
100 Technology Drive  
Suite 315  
Broomfield, CO 80021  
303.447.3100  
support@xeroshoes.com
